Guide to the Helen and Newton Harrison Papers M1797
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 9. Business Records, 1968-2010
  - Subseries 10. Memberships, 1972-1976
    - Memberships; Grandview Gallery, 1973-1974 (Box 173, Folder 13)
    - Memberships; Mandeville Gallery Art Council, 1989 (Box 173, Folder 14)
    - Memberships; Museum of Contemporary Art San Diego, 1996 (Box 173, Folder 15)
    - Memberships; Women's Caucus for the Arts, 1975-1976, 1986, 1988-1989 (Box 173, Folder 16)
    - Memberships; Women's Caucus for the Arts, 1988 (Flat-box 277, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 11. Notes, 1969-2009
    This subseries consists of loose papers, notes, and sketches kept by the Harrisons. The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Notes, 1969, 1971-1973, 1976, 1979, 1983, 1985, 1989-1993, 2009 (Box 173, Folder 17)
    - Notes, undated (Box 173, Folders 18-19, Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 12. Permissions, 1971-2009
    This subseries consists of correspondence requesting permission from the Harrisons to use their work in published material. The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Permissions, 1971, 1979, 1981, 1987-1989, 1991, 1993-1994, 1997-1999 (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - Permissions, 2000-2001, 2003-2005, 2007-2009 (Box 174, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 13. Ronald Feldman Fine Arts, 1975-2007
    This subseries consists of records documenting the Harrisons’ involvement with Ronald Feldman Fine Arts in New York City, New York, their gallery representation since 1974. It includes the agreement between the Harrisons and Ronald Feldman Fine Arts, correspondence, publicity, floorplans, mailing lists, and notes. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Agreement, 1981 (Box 174, Folder 4)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Correspondence, 1977-1975, 1987 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Correspondence, 1989-1996, 2001, 2003, 2006-2007, undated (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Harrison biographies, 1975-1976, 1978 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Harrison work exhibited, 1974 (Box 174, Folder 8)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Financial, 1976, 1980, 1983, 1986, 1989, undated (Box 174, Folder 9)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Floorplans, 1980, undated (Box 174, Folder 10)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Mailing list, undated (Box 174, Folder 11)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Notes, undated (Box 174, Folder 12)
    - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts; Proposal for the São Paulo Bienal: An Analogy for the Great Amazon Basin, undated (Box 174, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 14. Submissions and proposals, 1971-2007
    This subseries consists of the Harrisons’ various submissions and proposals for future work, projects, programs, posters, and exhibitions. It includes correspondence, text, publicity, and application material. The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    For the bulk of the Harrisons’ work, see Series 2. Project Files and Series 3. Project Binders.
    - Submissions and proposals; Exhibition at the Guggenheim Museum, 1971, 1974 (Box 174, Folder 14)
    - Submissions and proposals; Whitney Annual, 1972 (Box 174, Folder 15)
    - Submissions and proposals; MATRIX program at the University of California, Berkeley, 1980, 1982 (Box 174, Folder 16)
    - Submissions and proposals; Art in Public Places project at Inspiration Point, Newport Beach, CA, 1987 (Box 175, Folder 1)
    - Submissions and proposals; Lower Rio Grande Valley Agrarian Community Project, 1988 (Box 175, Folder 2)
    - Submissions and proposals; Pepper Canyon at the University of California, San Diego, 1989 (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - Submissions and proposals; Art enrichment project for the new main branch San Francisco Library, 1990 (Box 175, Folder 4)
    - Submissions and proposals; Balboa Park, 1990, undated (Box 175, Folder 5)
    - Submissions and proposals; New England Holocaust Memorial Competition, 1990-1991 (Box 175, Folder 6)
    - Submissions and proposals; São Paulo proposal, 1990 (Box 175, Folder 7)
    - Submissions and proposals; Kostabi World Tower, 1991 (Box 175, Folder 8)
    - Submissions and proposals; Phoenix Arts Commission Public Art Program, 1991 (Box 175, Folder 9)
    - Submissions and proposals; City of Philadelphia's Percent for Art Program, 1992 (Box 175, Folder 10)
    - Submissions and proposals; A Call for Sustainable Community Solutions, 1993 (Box 175, Folder 11)
    - Submissions and proposals; General Services Administration's Art-in-Architecture Program: Edward T. Gignoux Federal Courthouse, 1993 (Box 175, Folder 12)
    - Submissions and proposals; Los Angeles Metropolitan Transportation Authority, 1993-1994 (Box 175, Folder 13)
    - Submissions and proposals; Raleigh Art Commission Capital Boulevard Public Art Project, 1993 (Box 175, Folder 14)
    - Submissions and proposals; San Francisco Art Commission Capital Airport Projects, 1993-1994 (Box 175, Folder 15)
    - Submissions and proposals; Conference proposal in Chicago, 1994 (Box 175, Folder 16)
    - Submissions and proposals; Pasadena City College Sculpture Garden, 1995 (Box 175, Folder 17)
    - Submissions and proposals; Beverly Hills Post Office, 1998 (Box 175, Folder 18)
    - Submissions and proposals; Proposal for the Establishment of the Centre for Urban & Regional Ecology, 1999 (Box 175, Folder 19)
    - Submissions and proposals; Papago Salado Trail, 2002 (Box 175, Folder 20)
    - Submissions and proposals; Crossover UK conference proposal, 2003 (Box 175, Folder 21)
    - Submissions and proposals; Legacy of Beuys online exhibition, 2004-2005 (Box 175, Folder 22)
    - Submissions and proposals; Exhibition proposal from Patricia Watts, 2006 (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - Submissions and proposals; Los Angeles and the Rising of Waters, 2006-2007 (Box 176, Folder 2)
    - Submissions and proposals; Central Park at Playa Vista, 2007 (Box 176, Folder 3)
    - Submissions and proposals; Greenhouse Earth at Google, 2007 (Box 176, Folder 4)
    - Submissions and proposals; Chicago River proposal "Mouth to Mouth", undated (Box 176, Folder 5)
    - Submissions and proposals; Disappearing Fence and Sleepstack, undated (Box 176, Folder 6)
    - Submissions and proposals; Eastern Oasis Enhancement Project: Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, undated (Box 176, Folder 7)
    - Submissions and proposals; Miscellaneous competition information, 1994 (Flat-box 277, Folder 12)
    - Submissions and proposals; Miscellaneous competition posters, 1986, 1993-1994 (Map-folder 394)
    - Submissions and proposals; New England Holocaust Memorial Competition, 1990-1991 (Map-folder 395)
    - Submissions and proposals; On Valuing the Farms, the Forests, the Rivers, the Meadows and the City of Frankfurt Within its Own Borders: The Great Encircling Walk, undated (Box 176, Folder 8)
    - Submissions and proposals; Post Office Square Concept Narrative, undated (Box 176, Folder 9)
    - Submissions and proposals; Toward the Invention of a New Multi-layered Environmental Form: A Stability, undated (Box 176, Folder 10)
    - Submissions and proposals; Washington Square Park: Zones of Maximum Safety, undated (Box 176, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 15. Travel records, 1985-2010
    This subseries consists of the Harrisons’ work travel records. The bulk of the material is arranged by the trip it documents. Most of the trips were in the United States, England, Germany, and Italy. It includes correspondence, ticketing information, schedules, and itineraries. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Travel records; Berlin trip, circa 1988-1989 (Box 176, Folder 12)
    - Travel records; Berlin trip, circa 1988-1989 (Map-folder 470)
    - Travel records; England, 1997-1998, 2005 (Box 176, Folder 13)
    - Travel records; England, 2005 (Box 176, Folder 14)
    - Travel records; European travel, 1997, 2005 (Box 176, Folder 15)
    - Travel records; Germany, 1997, 2005 (Box 176, Folder 16)
    - Travel records; Greenhouse Britain Tour, 2005-2007 (Box 176, Folders 17-18)
    - Travel records; Italy, 2005 (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - Travel records; Misc., 1973, 1985, 1997-2001, 2006, 2009-2010, undated (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - Travel records; New York trip, 2006 (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - Travel records; United States, 2005 (Box 177, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 16. Vendors, 1982-1991
    This subseries consists of publicity, mailers, and contact information that the Harrisons collected on vendors they worked with or were interested in working with on future projects. The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Vendors, 1982, 1991, undated (Box 177, Folder 5)
- Series 10. University of California, San Diego (UCSD), 1967 - 2010
  This series contains records documenting the years that both Helen Mayer Harrison and Newton Harrison worked at the University of California, San Diego. Newton worked as a professor. Helen worked at UCSD’s University Extension and as a professor. The records include material from various departments including University Extension and Visual Arts, contracts and agreements, basic information on UCSD, the Harrisons’ UCSD biographies, correspondence, applications, committee information, faculty art shows, Academic Senate grants, maps, and campus planning. Of note is correspondence documenting the Harrisons’ request to split their professorship in 1979 and Helen’s 1972 letter of resignation from her position at the University Extension. Also included is the consulting agreement with Sam Naitich for Newton’s “Sky Pieces,” which became the “Artificial Aurora Borealis.” Material is arranged by type and then alphabetically.
  - Academic Affairs Office; Academic Archives Newton Harrison, 1975 (Box 177, Folder 6)
  - Academic Senate; Ballot, 2010 (Box 177, Folder 7)
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Academic Personnel, 1981, undated (Box 177, Folder 8)
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Book of Lagoons, 1984 (Box 177, Folder 9)
    Grant Number
    No grant #
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, A Consideration of the Strip Mines of Maravia, 1990-1991 (Box 177, Folder 10)
    #RQ 230-G
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Development of a System of Complex Shape Making for Sculpture, Using Foam as a Matrix, 1990-1991 (Box 177, Folder 11)
    #300
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Devil's Gate: A Refugia for Pasadena - an experimental videotape, 1986-1987 (Box 177, Folder 12)
    #RK225-G
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Full Farm Condensed, 1972 (Box 177, Folder 13)
    #726
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, A Grand Round for San Diego, 1987 (Box 177, Folder 14)
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Issue of Art-Rite, 1979 (Box 177, Folder 15)
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Lagoon, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 16)
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Research Travel Grant to become familiar with artists working in the Berkeley area and attend his own show opening at Mills College, 1969 (Box 177, Folder 17)
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Research Travel Grant to present at the College Art Association meeting in Washington, D.C., 1978-1979 (Box 177, Folder 18)
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Research Travel Grant to present paper Trümmerflora on the Topographie of Terrors at a memorial symposium in Berlin, 1988 (Box 177, Folder 19)
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, The Sculptural Possibilities of High Density Foam, 1967 (Box 177, Folder 20)
    #201
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, The Seven Lagoons, 1975 (Box 177, Folder 21)
    #846
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Tithing the Sava, 1988-1989 (Box 177, Folder 22)
    # RN 244-0, RP 270-G
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, The Use of Optics to Extend the Affective Power of Glow Discharges and Plasmas as an Expressive Medium, 1970-1971 (Box 177, Folder 23)
    #506
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Unidentified grant, 1969 (Box 177, Folder 24)
    #415
  - Academic Senate; Committee on Research, Unidentified grant, 1991 (Box 177, Folder 25)
  - Academic Senate; Officers and committees, 1985-1986 (Box 177, Folder 26)
  - Agreements; Consulting Agreement with Sam Naitich for Sky Pieces (or Aurora Borealis), 1970-1971 (Box 177, Folder 27)
  - Basic information on UCSD, undated (Box 177, Folder 28)
  - Biographies and employment status for Helen Mayer Harrison [RESTRICTED], 1971-1972, 1979 (Box 262, Folder 14)
  - Biographies and employment status for Helen Mayer Harrison, 1971-1972, 1979, 1981-1989 (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - Biographies and employment status for Newton Harrison [RESTRICTED], 1970 (Box 262, Folder 15)
  - Biographies and employment status for Newton Harrison, 1980-1987 (Box 178, Folder 2)
  - Campus planning; Central Campus Landscape Plan, 1989-1990 (Box 178, Folder 3)
  - Campus planning; Central Library Addition - Plaza, 1990 (Box 178, Folder 4)
  - Campus planning; Central Library Plaza and Related Circulation Elements, undated (Box 178, Folder 5)
  - Campus planning; Facilities Manual, 1977, 1983, 1986 (Box 178, Folder 6)
  - Campus planning; Landscape architecture firms, 1987, 1989-1990 (Box 178, Folder 7)
  - Campus planning; Maps, undated (Box 178, Folder 8)
  - Campus planning, Maps, undated (Flat-box 277, Folder 13)
  - Campus planning; Notes, undated (Box 178, Folder 9)
  - Campus planning; UCSD General Campus: A Space Plan for the I&R Departments into the Eighties, 1977 (Box 178, Folder 10)
  - Carlson Travel Network [RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 262, Folder 16)
  - Center for Music Experiment, 1978-1981 (Box 178, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Status of Women, 1989-1991 (Box 178, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1969, 1971-1974, 1976-1979 (Box 178, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 1972, 1978-1979, 1984, 1994 (Box 262, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 178, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1995, 1999, undated (Box 178, Folder 15)
  - Faculty shows, 1976, 1988 (Box 178, Folder 16)
  - Fellowships, 1971, 1989 (Box 178, Folder 17)
  - Fifth College; Making the Modern World, 1989-1990 (Box 178, Folder 18)
  - Forms, 1981-1982, 1989, 2001, undated (Box 178, Folder 19)
  - Guidelines for the Selection of Design Professionals, 1993 (Box 179, Folder 1)
  - Leave [RESTRICTED], 1971, 1979 (Box 262, Folder 18)
  - Patent for Color Theory for Automatic Selection and Correlation, 1968 (Box 179, Folder 2)
  - Project for Music Experiment, undated (Box 179, Folder 3)
  - Proposal for a Center of Ecological Restoration, undated (Box 179, Folder 4)
  - School of Architecture; Appointments and promotions, 1991-1992 (Box 179, Folder 5)
  - School of Architecture; Appointments and promotions [RESTRICTED], 1991-1992 (Box 262, Folder 19)
  - School of Architecture; Course descriptions by the Harrisons, 1992 (Box 179, Folder 6)
  - School of Architecture; Proposal to Establish the School of Architecture, undated (Box 179, Folder 7)
  - School of Architecture; Newsletters, 1990-1991 (Box 179, Folder 8)
  - School of Architecture; Unidentified Conference, 1990 (Box 179, Folder 9)
  - Statement of Intent; Newton Harrison's sabbatical, undated (Box 179, Folder 10)
  - Stewart Foundation / UCSD sculpture project, 1981 (Box 179, Folder 11)
  - Third College; Agreement for Professional Service for Master Planning, Third College, University of California, San Diego, 1970 (Box 179, Folder 12)
  - Third College; Brief Statement of Nature and Purpose of Third College, undated (Box 179, Folder 13)
  - Third College; Building Advisory Committee for Residence Halls, 1969 (Box 179, Folder 14)
  - Third College; Chancellor's Reply to Demands on the Structure and Governance of Third College as Presented by BSC and Maya, 3-14-1969 (Box 179, Folder 15)
  - Third College; Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 179, Folder 16)
  - Third College; Costs of Consulting to Third College UCSD, 1969 (Box 179, Folder 17)
  - Third College; Lumumba-Zapata College, undated (Box 179, Folder 18)
  - Third College; Masterplan with floorplans, 1970 (Box 179, Folder 19)
  - Third College; Project Planning Guide, 1969-1970 (Box 179, Folder 20)
  - Third College; A Proposal for the Funding of an Investigation of User-Requirements for the Third College at the University of California, San Diego, 1970 (Box 179, Folder 21)
  - Third College; Report by the Sub-Committee on Governance, undated (Box 179, Folder 22)
  - UCSD Foundation, undated (Box 179, Folder 23)
  - UCSD Services Directory, 1982 (Box 179, Folder 24)
  - University Extension; Assessment of Helen Mayer Harrison, undated (Box 179, Folder 25)
  - University Extension; Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 179, Folder 26)
  - University Extension; Course Format, undated (Box 179, Folder 27)
  - University Extension; The Human Brain in Relation to War and Peace, Returning Scholars Association, 1990 (Box 179, Folder 28)
  - Visual Arts Department; Budget Report Breakdown, undated (Box 179, Folder 29)
  - Visual Arts Department; Course, Art and Literature: Narratives, Paintings and Maps, 1982 (Box 179, Folder 30)
  - Visual Arts Department; Course, Evaluations for Helen Mayer Harrison, 1982-1992 (Box 179, Folder 31)
  - Visual Arts Department; Course, Evaluations for Newton Harrison, 1988 (Box 179, Folder 32)
  - Visual Arts Department; Courses, Charting Class (Newton Harrison) [RESTRICTED], 1990 (Box 262, Folder 20)
  - Visual Arts Department; Courses, Prospectus for an Experimental Design Course, undated (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - Visual Arts Department; Courses, Summer '72 courses pending, 1972, undated (Box 180, Folder 2)
  - Visual Arts Department; Courses, Teaching Schedule Preference, 1993 (Box 180, Folder 3)
    Helen Harrison
  - Visual Arts Department; Faculty, 1981-1982, 1992, 1994, 1999 (Box 180, Folder 4)
  - Visual Arts Department; Graduate students [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Box 262, Folder 21)
  - Visual Arts Department; Graduate students, 1992, 1996 (Box 180, Folder 5)
  - Visual Arts Department; Harrisons' business card, undated (Box 180, Folder 6)
  - Visual Arts Department; The Idea of an Institute, undated (Box 180, Folder 7)
  - Visual Arts Department; Students, 1983, 1992-1993 (Box 180, Folder 8)
  - Visual Arts Department; Studio Majors, undated (Box 180, Folder 9)
    Newton Harrison
- Series 11. University of California, Santa Cruz (UCSC), 2005-2010
  This series contains correspondence, research, planning, notes, and a proposal about starting an art PhD program at UCSC. Newton Harrison was hired as a recall professor to help start the Art Practice: A Whole Systems Approach with Global Reach PhD program. While at UCSC, Newton worked closely with Elizabeth (Beth) Stephens, the chair of the art department. Material is arranged by type and then alphabetically.
  - Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 180, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 180, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 180, Folders 12-17, Box 181, Folders 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 2010 (Box 181, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 181, Folder 4)
  - DANM graduate program [RESTRICTED], 2010 (Box 262, Folder 22)
  - DANM graduate program, undated (Box 181, Folder 5)
    Item removed to be housed with computer media / born-digital material. Box 264 Item #: M1797_CM 340 Title: DANM Visiting Day Presentation Format: CD
  - PhD program; Planning and notes, 2005, 2007-2009, undated (Box 181, Folders 6-7)
  - PhD program; Proposal, circa 2007-2009 (Box 181, Folder 8)
  - PhD program; Research, Faculty, 2009-2010 (Box 181, Folders 9-10, Box 182, Folder 1-3)
  - PhD program; Research, Misc., 2008-2009 (Box 182, Folder 4)
- Series 12. Writings, 1957-2003
  This series contains published and unpublished drafts of written material by the Harrisons. The bulk of the material are articles and essays. The material is arranged alphabetically.
  - "Breathing Space for the Sava River" in IS Journal #10, 1990 (Box 182, Folder 5)
  - "Breathing Space for the Sava River" in New Observations, 1991 (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - "The Bridge Builder", undated (Box 182, Folder 7)
  - "Commissions" in The Business of Art, 1998 (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - "Dropouts and a 'Design for Living" in New Perspectives on Poverty, 1965 (Box 182, Folder 9)
  - "Five Recent Works in Transaction with the Cultural Landscape", undated (Box 182, Folder 10)
  - "Formalism in Newton Harrison's Work", circa 1970-1975 (Box 182, Folder 11)
  - "From There to Here", 2002 (Box 182, Folder 12)
  - "Geschichten aus einem unorthodoxen Klassenzimmer" in Forensische Psychiatrie und Psychotherapie, 1997-1998 (Box 182, Folder 13)
  - Harrison Studio Constitution, undated (Box 182, Folder 14)
  - "The Harrison Studio: Helen Mayer Harrison, Newton Harrison and Associates, undated (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Helen Mayer Harrison's drafts, notes, and poetry, 1959-1960, undated (Box 183, Folders 2-3)
  - "Houston Statement Ruminations", circa 1970-1975 (Box 183, Folder 4)
  - "Immigrants", 1957-1960 (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - "LACMA Changes Point to Team Dissolution" in Los Angeles Times, 1993 (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - "Newton Harrison", circa 1970-1975 (Box 183, Folder 7)
  - "Newton Harrison: A Brief Account of My Career as a Creative Artist", circa 1970-1975 (Box 183, Folder 8)
  - "Newton Harrison - Brief Statement of Plans", circa 1970-1975 (Box 183, Folder 9)
  - "Notes on a Recent Project" in the International Repertory of the Literature of Art, 1977 (Box 183, Folder 10)
  - "Notes on a Recent Project" in LAICA Journal, 1977 (Box 183, Folder 11)
  - "On Art and Farming", circa 1970-1975 (Box 183, Folder 12)
  - "On Collaboration", 1978 (Box 183, Folder 13)
  - "On Creativity in the Work", undated (Box 183, Folder 14)
  - "On Dissipative Structures", undated (Box 183, Folder 15)
  - "On Icons, Networks, Feedback Loops and Stability Domains", undated (Box 183, Folder 16)
  - "On Our Process", undated (Box 183, Folder 17)
  - "On Shaping the Biodiversity Sphere", undated (Box 183, Folder 18)
  - "On the Environment", undated (Box 183, Folder 19)
  - "One Full Work and Part of Another" in New Wilderness Letter, 1977-1978 (Box 183, Folder 20)
  - "Plans", circa 1970-1975 (Box 183, Folder 21)
  - "Ruminations: Dialoguing with a Cow", circa 1970-1975 (Box 183, Folder 22)
  - "Sea Grant: Second Narrative and Two Precedent Works" in Studio International, 1974 (Box 183, Folder 23)
  - "Shifting Positions Toward the Earth: Art and Environmental Awareness" in Leonardo, 1993 (Box 183, Folder 24, Box 184, Folder 1)
  - "Shifting Positions Toward the Earth: Art and Environmental Awareness" in Women, Art, and Technology, 2002-2003 (Box 184, Folder 2)
  - "The Sixth Lagoon: On Metaphor and Discourse" in Arrested Rivers, 1993 (Box 184, Folder 3)
  - Statement on Daniel Buren's work, 1974 (Box 184, Folder 4)
  - "Stories", 1998 (Box 184, Folder 5)
  - "Stories from an Unorthodox Classroom: A Talk by Newton Harrison", undated (Box 184, Folder 6)
  - "A Short Discussion of Michelangelo, Rodin and Epstein, and Sculptural Values", undated (Box 184, Folder 7)
  - "A Story of Becoming: Landscape Creation Through an Art / Science Dynamic", undated (Box 184, Folder 8)
    by Les Firbank, Helen Mayer Harrison, Newton Harrison, David Haley and Bruce Griffith
  - "Talking Waters", 1980 (Box 184, Folder 9)
  - Text for Echo Art book titled Watersheds, undated (Box 184, Folder 10)
  - "To Avert Catastrophe on the Roof of the World" in Kyoto Journal, 2010 (Box 184, Folder 11)
  - "Toward a New Curriculum Formation: Notes from the Harrison Studio", undated (Box 184, Folder 12)
  - "Trümmerflora on the Topography of Terrors" in WhiteWalls, 1990 (Box 184, Folder 13)
  - "Two Meditations, Two Commentaries and Eight Questions on the Great Lakes of North America" in New Wilderness Letter, 1979 (Box 184, Folder 14)
  - "The Universe as Discourse", undated (Box 184, Folder 15)
  - Untitled pieces by the Harrisons about their work, undated (Box 184, Folder 16)
  - "Watershed Thinking", undated (Box 184, Folder 17)